<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Samvet</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Samvet</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 15:05:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swetankambar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/running/reflections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 15:05:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/running/reflections/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="looking-back">Looking Back&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Indeterminate Relationships</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/indeterminate_relationships/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/indeterminate_relationships/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/image/indeterminate_relationships.png" alt="comic2" title="Indeterminate Relationships">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Time Filter</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/time_filter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/time_filter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Barry Schwartz wrote &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice">The paradox of choice&lt;/a> in 2004, and its relevance is indubitable today in 2020. The argument that probably most of us would be happy if there are a lesser number of choices has increased its relevance over time.
The current age is of an apparent abundance, and like the real devil, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a problem. If anything, it feels like the happiest time of our lives because we need not think twice to get what we want.
To all those who don&amp;rsquo;t think this is a real issue, this article is not for you. It is not an argument to prove the problem of abundance or the paradox of having a large number of choices. For others, one of my method to diminish the damage to my attention span, focus and happiness is by using time as a filter. This implies using a time threshold to decide whether to consume something or not. This is like putting a low pass filter that will let only slow varying things to pass, and attenuate anything that is changing suddenly. This approach works well to decide things like :&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living in the past</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/living_in_past/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/living_in_past/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://swetankambar.github.io/junkomics/image/living_in_past.png" alt="comic1" title="You read this comic in the past and now you are reading the caption in the past...">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fat Tony vs Socrates</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/fat_tony_vs_socrates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/fat_tony_vs_socrates/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="conversation-between-socrates-and-fat-tony">Conversation between &lt;strong>Socrates&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Fat Tony&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Antifragile is a great idea and one without which life can/must/should not be imagined, and nnt has made the book so real and original that it almost feels like talking to a person. I have had my conflicts with the book at places. This is an alternate interpretation of a dialogue between &lt;strong>Fat Tony&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Socrates&lt;/strong> in Chapter 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fat Tony&lt;/strong>: Get lost socrates, You are asking me to define what is the difference between pious and non pious, do I really need to be able to tell you what it is to be able to conduct a pious action?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aphorisms</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/aphorisms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/perspectives/aphorisms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="management">Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Time Management&lt;/em>: To make promise to people and to ensure that you deliver each one of them. There is no such learnable skill as time-management, it is an expression of integrity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Anger Management&lt;/em>: Have a control loop running in the background that checks evaluates the cause of anger. In many cases, it is the fear that something might be true and unpleasant at the same time. At many other times, it is our own expectations that make us angry.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Noise Figure Calculation</title><link>https://swetankambar.github.io/rf-experiments/noise_figure_calculation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swetankambar.github.io/rf-experiments/noise_figure_calculation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="noise-figure-calculation">Noise Figure Calculation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I got a USRP device at hand and the post uses it as the radio whose noise figure has to be estimated. The method described below is generic and is valid for any RF receiver.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$$
Noise, Figure= 10*log_{10}(Noise ,Factor) \[3mm]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noise, Factor=\frac{SNR_{IN}}{SNR_{OUT}}\[3mm]
$$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following approach is taken to calculate the NF experimentally:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provide input to the USRP RIO using a known signal generator with a low amplitude ~-70dBm. This signal should be measured by a VSA or SA to check the signal input to USRP RIO.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>